{
    "id": "53c5a8ee7fa648598262dc4ca911d724",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I am confident …………………….. I will win.",
            "description": "We use that to introduce a noun clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "if",
                "whether"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. she heard the news, she fainted.",
            "description": "As soon as is used to connect two actions that happen in quick succession. ",
            "answers": [
                "As soon as",
                "As early as",
                "Provided that"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He worked diligently ………………………….. he could build a successful business.",
            "description": "So that indicates the purpose.",
            "answers": [
                "so that",
                "so as to",
                "in order to"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. he does not arrive on time, we will go without him.",
            "description": "We use if to express a condition. ",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Unless",
                "Whether"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He died in the village ……………………….. he was born.",
            "description": "We can use where to introduce adverb clauses of place.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "where"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The children were not fully prepared ……………………….. they delivered a splendid performance.",
            "description": "We use but to connect two contrasting ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "but",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She earns more ……………………….. him.",
            "description": "We use than after a comparative expression.",
            "answers": [
                "compared to",
                "than",
                "then"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. you start now, you will be able to catch the first bus.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Unless",
                "As long as"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… he apologizes, we will not take him back.",
            "description": "Unless is similar to if not.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Unless",
                "In case"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She is a kind woman ……………………… everybody respects.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "whom",
                "which",
                "her"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Work hard …………………………… you will succeed.",
            "description": "And adds. ",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "as",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The child started crying …………………………. he was hungry.",
            "description": "Because gives the reason. ",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "hence",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}